Guide to the Walter LaFeber papers, 1961-2008.
LaFeber, Walter papers, 1961-2008
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Walter LaFeber papers, 1961-2008.
14-17-2624
LaFeber, Walter.
21.5 cubic ft.
Professional papers.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Professional papers of Walter LaFeber, a Cornell University historian specializing in American foreign policy.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor of History, Cornell University.
Walter LaFeber graduated from Hanover College in 1955, received a master's degree from Stanford University in 1956 and a Ph.D. from the University of Wisconsin in 1959. He came to Cornell in 1963 and is currently the Marie Underhill Noll Professor of American History. He specializes in American foreign policy. His major works include The New Empire: An Interpretation of American Expansion, America; Russia and the Cold War; and The Panama Canal: The Crisis in Historical Perspective; as well as editing John Q. Adams and the American Continental Empire.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Professional papers relating to his research, teaching, and writing about American foreign policy.
SUBJECTS
Names:
LaFeber, Walter.; Cornell University. Dept. of History.
Subjects:
College teachers.
Places:
United States--Foreign relations.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Closed for research for five years after the death of the donor and his spouse.
CONTAINER LIST
- Westminster Foundation; John Quincey Adams Manuscript; miscellaneous correspondence; Correspondence January-June 1976; old recommendations. [Poor condition.], 1961-1976 (Box 1)
- Correspondence. University stuff; Crowell book; CU Presidential Commission, 1967 (Box 2)
- Cornell Aeronautical Lab; Dartmouth Conference; Correspondence January-September 1969., 1969 (Box 3)
- Cornell Aeronautical Lab; Correspondence, 1971 (Box 4)
- Correspondence. State Department Advisory Committee on Foreign Relation; Chelsea House Publisher) Correspondence. Pacific Historic Review., 1972-1977 (Box 5)
- Correspondence between 1976-1978, 1976-1979 (Box 6)
- Constitution correspondence, Correspondence from 1968, 1980, 1981, and some from 1978-1980, 1968-1981 (Box 7)
- FDR Foundation; Reuben Askew for President file; file on BPA course 1981-1983; 1984 correspondence, 1981-1984 (Box 8)
- OAH-Hanington Paper; 1985-1986 correspondence; Free Speech commission 1986-1987; Seward book, 1985-1987 (Box 9)
- Book Contracts and permissions; July-December 1984; January-June 1985, 1984-1985 (Box 10)
- July-December 1987; January-June 1988. Matthew McHugh Congress 1975-July-December 1986; a cassettes., 1975-1986 (Box 11)
- Correspondence January-June 1987, 1987 (Box 12)
- January-June 1989, January-June 1990, 1989-1990 (Box 13)
- July-December 1989; July-December 1990; January-June 1991, 1989-1991 (Box 14)
- Correspondence 1975; July-December 1978; letters 1971; Pulitzer Prize July 1975, 1971-1978 (Box 15)
- May-June correspondence., 1992 (Box 16, Folder 1)
- July 1989-February 1992 correspondence., 1989-1992 (Box 16, Folder 2)
- March-April 1992 correspondence, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 3)
- April-June 1992 correspondence, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 4)
- May-July 1992 correspondence, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 5)
- July-August 1992 correspondence, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 6)
- September-October 1992 correspondence, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 7)
- November 1992 correspondence, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 8)
- December 1992 correspondence, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 9)
- Miscellaneous (1982-February 1992) filed with folders for March-December 1992., 1992 (Box 16, Folder 10)
- January 1992 correspondence, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 11)
- February-March 1992 correspondence, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 12)
- April 1992 correspondence, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 13)
- May-June 1992 correspondence, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 14)
- Miscellaneous (April 1970- December 1991) filed with folders for January-October 1992, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 15)
- July 1992 correspondence, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 16)
- August-September 1992 correspondence, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 17)
- September 1992 correspondence, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 18)
- October 1992 correspondence, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 19)
- November 1992 correspondence, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 20)
- December 1993 correspondence, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 21)
- October 1996-January 1997 correspondence, 1997 (Box 16, Folder 22)
- February 1997 correspondence, 1997 (Box 16, Folder 23)
- March 1997 correspondence, 1997 (Box 16, Folder 24)
- Apr. 1997 correspondence, 1997 (Box 16, Folder 25)
- May 1997 correspondence, 1997 (Box 16, Folder 26)
- May 1997 correspondence, 1997 (Box 16, Folder 27)
- June 1997 correspondence, 1997 (Box 16, Folder 28)
- July 1997 correspondence, 1997 (Box 16, Folder 29)
- August 1997 correspondence, 1997 (Box 16, Folder 30)
- September 1997 correspondence, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 1)
- October 1997 correspondence, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 2)
- November 1997 correspondence, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 3)
- December 1997 correspondence, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 4)
- "Harry Truman" PBS-TV-"The American Experience" program (4 hours), 1997 (Box 17, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, Part II of Truman, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 6)
- Part three of Truman; Series themes, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 7)
- TR-draft script for parts 1, 2 and 3; correspondence, 1994-96 (Box 17, Folder 8)
- "Theodore Roosevelt" PBS-TV-"American Experience" program - 4 hours., 1995 (Box 17, Folder 9)
- The American Experience - Theodore Roosevelt, Mar. 3, 1995: Program Script, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 10)
- Eric Delman phone conversations; his memos on Bush-Pentagon Russian Policy, 1993 (Box 17, Folder 11)
- Eric Delman's The End of the Cold War: The Triumph of Idealpolitik, 1993 (Box 17, Folder 12)
- Copy of letter on proposal of the committee on Diplomatic Documentation, 1982-1984 (Box 17, Folder 13)
- Correspondence and reviews relating to "Inevitable Revolutionary: The United States in Central America", 1983-1985 (Box 17, Folder 14)
- Correspondence, newspaper articles and reviews relating to "Inevitable Revolutionary: The United States in Central America", 1984-1988 (Box 17, Folder 15)
- USSR correspondence and materials, 1967-1980 (Box 17, Folder 16)
- USSR correspondence and materials, 1980-1988 (Box 17, Folder 17)
- USSR correspondence and materials, 1988-1991 (Box 17, Folder 18)
- Correspondence, 1992 + Before (Box 18, Folder 1)
- Correspondence January-June (1), 1994 (Box 18, Folder 2)
- Correspondence January-June (2), 1994 (Box 18, Folder 3)
- Correspondence January-June (3), 1994 (Box 18, Folder 4)
- Correspondence July-December (1), 1994 (Box 18, Folder 5)
- Correspondence July-December (2), 1994 (Box 18, Folder 6)
- Correspondence July-December (3), 1994 (Box 18, Folder 7)
- Correspondence January-June (1), 1994 (Box 18, Folder 8)
- Correspondence January-June (2), 1995 (Box 18, Folder 9)
- Correspondence January-June (3), 1995 (Box 18, Folder 10)
- Correspondence July-December (1), 1995 (Box 18, Folder 11)
- Correspondence July-December (2), 1995 (Box 18, Folder 12)
- Correspondence January-June (1), 1996 (Box 18, Folder 13)
- Correspondence January-June (2), 1996 (Box 18, Folder 14)
- Correspondence January-June (3), 1996 (Box 18, Folder 15)
- Correspondence July-December (1), 1996 (Box 18, Folder 16)
- Correspondence July-December (2), 1996 (Box 18, Folder 17)
- Correspondence July-December (3), 1996 (Box 18, Folder 18)
- Correspondence January-June, 1997 (Box 18, Folder 19)
- Correspondence January-June (1), 1998 (Box 19, Folder 1)
- Correspondence January-July (2), 1998 (Box 19, Folder 2)
- Correspondence January-July (2), 1998 (Box 19, Folder 2)
- Correspondence January-July (3), 1998 (Box 19, Folder 3)
- Correspondence July-December (1), 1998 (Box 19, Folder 4)
- Correspondence July-December (2), 1998 (Box 19, Folder 5)
- Correspondence "1900" Television Project for PBS, 1997-1998 (Box 19, Folder 6)
- The American Experience "1900" Script, 1996 (Box 19, Folder 7)
- Presidency of Society of Historians of American Foreign Relations, 1998-2000 (Box 19, Folder 8)
- Correspondence January-June, 1998 (Box 19, Folder 9)
- Correspondence July-December (1), 1999 (Box 19, Folder 10)
- Correspondence July-December (2), 1999 (Box 19, Folder 11)
- Correspondence January-June (2), 2000 (Box 19, Folder 12)
- Correspondence July-December 2000 (1), 2000 (Box 19, Folder 13)
- Correspondence July-December (2), 2000 (Box 19, Folder 14)
- Correspondence January-June (1), 2001 (Box 20, Folder 1)
- Correspondence January-June (2), 2001 (Box 20, Folder 2)
- Correspondence July-December (1), 2001 (Box 20, Folder 3)
- Correspondence July-December (2), 2001 (Box 20, Folder 4)
- Correspondence January-June (1), 2002 (Box 20, Folder 5)
- Correspondence January-June (2), 2002 (Box 20, Folder 6)
- Correspondence July-December (1), 2002 (Box 20, Folder 7)
- Correspondence July-December (2), 2002 (Box 20, Folder 8)
- Correspondence January-June (1), 2003 (Box 20, Folder 9)
- Correspondence January-June (2), 2003 (Box 20, Folder 10)
- Correspondence July-December (1), 2003 (Box 20, Folder 11)
- Correspondence July-December (2), 2003 (Box 20, Folder 12)
- Correspondence January-June (1), 2004 (Box 20, Folder 13)
- Correspondence January-June (2), 2004 (Box 20, Folder 14)
- Correspondence July 1972 - October 2000, 1972-2000 (Box 21, Folder 1)
- Miscellaneous Correspondence 1998-2006, 1998-2006 (Box 21, Folder 2)
- Miscellaneous Correspondence 1998-2006, 1998-2006 (Box 21, Folder 3)
- Correspondence 2001-2003, 2001-2003 (Box 21, Folder 4)
- Correspondence January-May, 2004 (Box 21, Folder 5)
- Correspondence June, 2004 (Box 21, Folder 6)
- Correspondence July, 2004 (Box 21, Folder 7)
- Correspondence August, 2004 (Box 21, Folder 8)
- Correspondence September, 2004 (Box 21, Folder 9)
- Correspondence October, 2004 (Box 21, Folder 10)
- Correspondence November, 2004 (Box 21, Folder 11)
- Correspondence December, 2004 (Box 21, Folder 12)
- Correspondence January, 2005 (Box 21, Folder 13)
- Correspondence February, 2005 (Box 21, Folder 14)
- Correspondence March, 2005 (Box 21, Folder 15)
- Correspondence April, 2005 (Box 21, Folder 16)
- Correspondence May, 2005 (Box 21, Folder 17)
- Correspondence June, 2005 (Box 21, Folder 18)
- Correspondence July, 2005 (Box 21, Folder 19)
- Correspondence August, 2005 (Box 21, Folder 20)
- Correspondence September, 2005 (Box 21, Folder 21)
- Correspondence October, 2005 (Box 21, Folder 22)
- Correspondence November, 2005 (Box 21, Folder 23)
- Correspondence December, 2005 (Box 21, Folder 24)
- Correspondence January, 2006 (Box 21, Folder 25)
- Correspondence February, 2006 (Box 21, Folder 26)
- Correspondence March, 2006 (Box 21, Folder 27)
- Correspondence April, 2006 (Box 21, Folder 28)
- Correspondence May, 2006 (Box 21, Folder 29)
- Correspondence June, 2004 (Box 21, Folder 30)
- Correspondence July, 2006 (Box 21, Folder 31)
- Correspondence August, 2006 (Box 21, Folder 32)
- Correspondence September, 2006 (Box 21, Folder 33)
- Correspondence October, 2006 (Box 21, Folder 34)
- Correspondence November, 2006 (Box 21, Folder 35)
- Correspondence December, 2006 (Box 21, Folder 36)
- Photographs, 2004 (Box 21, Folder 37)
- Correspondence January-June, 2007 (Box 22, Folder 1)
- Correspondence July, 2007 (Box 22, Folder 2)
- Correspondence August, 2007 (Box 22, Folder 3)
- Correspondence September, 2007 (Box 22, Folder 4)
- Correspondence October, 2007 (Box 22, Folder 5)
- Correspondence November, 2007 (Box 22, Folder 6)
- Correspondence December, 2007 (Box 22, Folder 7)
- Photographs, 2007 - 2008 (Box 22, Folder 8)
- Correspondence January, 2008 (Box 22, Folder 9)
- Correspondence February, 2008 (Box 22, Folder 10)
- Correspondence March, 2008 (Box 22, Folder 11)
- Correspondence April, 2008 (Box 22, Folder 12)
- Correspondence May, 2008 (Box 22, Folder 13)
- Correspondence June - July, 2008 (Box 22, Folder 14)